Guide to the Marilyn Skolnick Papers, 1952-2009 AIS.2001.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Marilyn Skolnick Papers
1952-2009
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Skolnick, Marilyn
AIS.2001.01
100.3 Linear Feet (72 records center boxes, 3 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box)
Marilyn Skolnick, an avid environmentalist, was successful at pushing for change in transportation issues due to her participation in numerous environmental and transportation organizations throughout the western Pennsylvania area. The papers of Marilyn Skolnick mainly focus on material she collected from various organization and committee meetings. These papers include reports, correspondence, news clippings, memos, agendas, minutes, notifications, legal transcriptions, environmental information, and audio-visual material.
Biography
Marilyn Skolnick was born in Brooklyn, New York, in 1925. While in New York, she received her bachelor's degree in Geology at Brooklyn College, the University of the City of New York. Skolnick later received a master's degree in Anthropology from the University of Oklahoma and participated in additional post-graduate work at the State University of Iowa and the University of Texas. By 1998, Skolnick was listed in Marquis' Who's Who of American Women.
Skolnick began her career as an environmental and transportation activist when she moved to Houston, Texas, earlier in her life. The cause for her move was a job transfer on behalf of her husband, Herbert, at the Gulf Oil Corporation. Upon her arrival, the city of Houston had no public transportation system. On behalf of the Houston League of Women Voters, Skolnick advocated for one. In return for her transportation advocacy, the Houston mayor appointed Skolnick to a transit liaison committee. Unfortunately, she had little time to serve on this committee as her husband was transferred to Pittsburgh, Pa., in 1971.
Upon her arrival in Monroeville, Pa., Skolnick continued pursuing her interests in transportation issues. Beginning in 1971, she acted as an advocate for public transportation. She was able to do this through her active participation in the League of Women Voters as an observer to the Southwestern Pennsylvania Regional Planning Commission. In particular, Skolnick focused on issues relating to the Pittsburgh and Allegheny County region.
Skolnick can be considered an avid environmentalist. This can be seen in her participation in organizations such as the Sierra Club, the Group Against Smog and Pollution (GASP), the Allegheny County Health Department, the Southwestern Pennsylvania Regional Planning Commission, the Allegheny County Transit Council, and the Division of Air Quality. In addition to her participation in these environmental organizations, Skolnick was also an ardent reporter for causes related to air quality, hazardous waste, land use, clean water, and recycling. In relation to her desire to report, Skolnick hosted and produced a local Pittsburgh television show, "Focus on Issue." It was not uncommon for her to compose several articles in issues for the Allegheny Sierran (the newsletter of the Allegheny Group of the Sierra Club) i.e., "Is There a Maglev in Our Future?"
Skolnick was able to remain close to the causes by chairing various committees on air quality, conservation, and transportation. Her constant public involvement allowed for her to push for change in the areas of environment and transportation that she saw as necessary. Skolnick was president of the League of Women Voters in Monroeville from 1973 to 1975, and director of the League of Women Voters Pennsylvania from 1977 to 1985. Skolnick served as both a board member and Consumer Relations Chair for the Port Authority of Allegheny County (PAT). She served a a member of the Executive Committee (Excomm) for the Sierra Club as well as the chair of Transportation and Growth Management. She also served on committees and as chairperson for organizations such as the Pennsylvania Department of Environmental Resources, Small Business Assistance Program, the Transportation Research Board, Allegheny County Hazardous Waste Task Force, and the Monroeville Planning Commission.
Marilyn Skolnick was the recipient of numerous awards for her contributions in the environmental and transportation arenas. These awards include a Certificate of Recognition from J.C. Penny Golden Rule Award, the American Bar Association's Liberty Bell Award, YWCA of Greater Pittsburgh's "A Tribute to Women for Leadership in Community Service," Woman of the Year by the Monroeville Jaycees, Citizen of the Year by the Monroeville Times-Express, and the National Sierra Club Environmental Hero for Transportation. In addition, in 2002, Marilyn Skolnick was awarded the Lifetime Achievement Award from the Brooklyn College Alumni Association.
Marilyn Skolnick resided in Monroeville until her death in December 2016.
Scope and Content Notes
These papers document the efforts of Marilyn Skolnick to change the face of Pennsylvania transportation systems, mainly in the Pittsburgh, Allegheny County region. With a strong backing in environmentalism, Skolnick focused on changing transportation for the benefit of the environment and for the benefit of those in the community. Much of the materials contained in this collection come from Skolnick's participation in organizations and committees attempting to participate on behalf of the public for change. The collection mainly focuses on Skolnick's public involvement in the environmental and transportation spectrum and little on her life aside from these two issues.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Previous Citation
Marilyn Skolnick Papers, 1952-2009, AIS.2001.01, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Acquisition Information
Gift of Marilyn Skolnick in 2000. Additional material (audio-visual) donated in July 2013.
Related Material
Group Against Smog and Pollution (GASP) Records, 1971-1976, AIS.1979.21, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Sierra Club Pennsylvania Chapter Records, 1970-1997, AIS.2000.16, Archives & Special Collections, University of Pittsburgh Library System
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following seven series:
Series I. Environmental Issues, 1970-2002
Series II. Transportation, 1961-2004
Series III. Southwestern Pennsylvania Regional Planning Commission, 1979-2005
Series IV. Organizations, 1977-2002
Series V. Governmental Issues/Legislation, 1983-2006
Series VI. Correspondence/Notes, 1952-2001
Series VII. Audio-Visual Material, 1987-2009
Personal papers; Women; Environment; Local transit -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Women environmentalists -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Environmentalists -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Transportation -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Land use -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Pollution -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Air quality management -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Activists; Air quality -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Newsletters; Correspondence; Refuse and refuse disposal -- Pennsylvania; Sanitary landfills -- Pennsylvania; Pittsburgh (Pa.); Allegheny County (Pa.); Skolnick, Marilyn; Kochankowski, Robert; Millar, William; Pollack, Rita; Allegheny County (Pa.). Local Emergency Planning Committee; Allegheny County Transit Council; Allegheny County (Pa.). Health Department; American Public Transit Association; Pennsylvania. Department of Environmental Protection; Pennsylvania. Department of Environmental Resources; Pennsylvania. Department of Transportation; GASP (Pittsburgh, Pa.); League of Women Voters of Greater Pittsburgh; National Research Council (U.S.). Transportation Research Board; Southwestern Pennsylvania Commission; Southwestern Pennsylvania Regional Planning Commission; Sierra Club. Pennsylvania Chapter. Allegheny Group; Port Authority of Allegheny County; Pennsylvania Environmental Council
- Environmental Issues, 1970-2002; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Although Marilyn Skolnick's main focus was transportation, she was interested in various other environmental issues. Some of these environmental issues (air quality, land use, pollution, transportation, waste, water) are aligned with the transportation cause. However, Skolnick was interested in numerous other issues (Chambers Landfill Company, chemicals, recycling, urban development, wetlands, wildlife) which demonstrate her environmental interests beyond transportation and can been seen by her membership in the Sierra Club.
  Much of the material organized in this series was removed from the collection since it is published material and can be found elsewhere. This material included copies of U.S. Senate and U.S. House legislation on the subject of Growth Management, annual reports on air quality and air pollution rates for the Allegheny County reports and publications from the "Pittsburgh Energy Technology Center," the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), and the General Accounting Office (GAO). In relation to the Chambers Landfill Company, removals included reproductions of briefs, copies of resolutions and annual reports, reproduced records, waste management plans, and Pennsylvania Planning Codes.
  This series date from 1970 to 2002 and is arranged in twenty-seven subseries, alphabetically, by environmental issue.
  - Acid Rain, 1986-1997; 1.
    Scope and Content Note
    The documents in the Acid Rain subseries date from 1986 to 1997 and are arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1997 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Pennsylvanians for Acid Rain Control (PennARC), 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Air Quality, 1987-2002; 2.
    The material in the Air Quality subseries date from 1987 to 2002 and are arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - 1989-1999 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1990-1997 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1991-1996 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
    - 1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1992-1997 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
    - 1992-1998 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1993-1996 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1993-1999 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 1993-2001 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 1994 (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
    - 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 1994-2000 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - 1995 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - 1996 (Box 1, Folder 24-27)
    - 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - 1996-2001 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - 1998 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - 1999 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - 2000 (Box 1, Folder 34-35)
    - 2001 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Air and Waste Management Association, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Air Emails, 1997-2000 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Air Monitoring, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Air Monitoring Subcommittee, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Air Quality Committee A1F03, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Air Quality Email, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Air Quality Improvement Outreach, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Air Quality Plan Approval, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Air Quality Pittsburgh, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Air Quality Program, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Air Toxics Advisory Committee, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Air and Waste Management, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Allegheny County, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Allegheny County, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Allegheny County, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Allegheny County, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Allegheny County, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Allegheny County, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Allegheny County, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Allegheny County, Annual Report, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, 1998-2001 (Box 2, Folder 22-23)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, 2000-2001 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Air Quality Program, 1989-1999 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Air Quality Program, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 26-27)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Air Quality Program, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 28-30)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Air Quality Program, 1996-2000 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Air Quality Program, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Air Quality Program, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Air Quality Program, 1998-2001 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Air Quality Program, 1999-2001 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Air Quality Program, 2000-2002 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Air Quality Program, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Air Quality Program, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Air Toxics Subcommittee, 1988-1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Air Toxics Subcommittee, 1989-1991 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Air Toxics Subcommittee, 1990-1994 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Air Toxics Subcommittee, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Air Toxics Subcommittee, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Air Toxics Subcommittee, 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Air Toxics Subcommittee, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Air Toxics Subcommittee, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Air Toxics Subcommittee, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 17-18)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Bureau of Air Pollution Control, 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Bureau of Environmental Quality, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Bureau of Environmental Quality, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Bureau of Environmental Quality, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 22-23)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Bureau of Environmental Quality, 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Bureau of Environmental Quality, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 25-27)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Bureau of Environmental Quality, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Executive Summary, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Miscellaneous, undated (Box 3, Folder 30-31)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, PM 10 Subcommittee, 1987-1990 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, PM 10 Subcommittee, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, PM 10 Subcommittee, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, PM 10 Subcommittee, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, RACM Workgroup, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Regulations Subcommittee, 1988-1997 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Regulation Subcommittee, 1989-1992 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Regulation Subcommittee, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Regulation Subcommittee, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Status of the Clean Air Act, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Allegheny County Health Department, Traffic Study, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - American Lung Association, 1995-1997 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - American Lung Association, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - American Lung Association, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - American Lung Association, undated (Box 4, Folder 17-18)
    - American Lung Association, Air Pollution, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - American Lung Association, Ozone, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Clean Air, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Clean Air, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Clean Air, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Clean Air Act, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Clean Air Act, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Clean Air Act, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Clean Air Act, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 27-28)
    - Clean Air Act Amendments, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Clean Air Act Amendments, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Clean Air Act Articles, 1991-1996 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Clean Air Companies, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Clean Air Council, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Clean Air Council, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Clean Air Council Lawsuits, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Clean Air Council, Proposed Inspection and Maintenance Program, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Clean Air Meetings, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Clean Air Network, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Clean Air Network, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 39-42)
    - Clean Air Network, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Clean Air Network, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Clean Air Network, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Clean Air Network, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Clean Air Network, CANnections, 1992-2000 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Clean Air Network, Clean Air Leadership Meeting, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Clean Air Network, Conference Calls, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Clean Air Network, Correspondence, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Clean Air Network, Correspondence, Jayne Murdock, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
    - Clean Air Network, Correspondence, Sign on Letter, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Clean Air Network, Directory of Contacts, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Clean Air Network, Goals, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Clean Air Network, Memorandum, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Clean Air Network, National Leadership Conference, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Clean Air Network, Newsletters, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Clean Air Network, Newspaper Articles, 1991-1997 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Clean Air Network, OTAG Minutes, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Clean Air Network, Papers, Gail Whitaker, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Clean Air Network, Permit Program, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Clean Air Network, Public Hearing Testimony on National LEV, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Clean Air Network, Surface Transportation Policy Project, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Clean Air Network, Pennsylvanians for Clean Air, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Clean Air Operating Permit Program, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Clean Air Policy, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Clean Air Technologies Workshop, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Clean Air Transportation Report, 1991-1994 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Clean Air Transportation Report, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Clean Air Transportation Report, Newsletter, 1992-1997 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Clean Air Through Transportation Report, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Coke Plants, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Coke Plants, 1992-1998 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Coke Plants, Clairton Works, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Coke Plants, Clairton Works, Coke Oven, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Coke Plants, Clairton Sportsmen versus Pennsylvania Turnpike Commission, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Coke Plants, Coke Oven Negotiations, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Coke Plants, Neville Island, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Coke Plants, Neville Island, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Coke Plants, Neville Island, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Conformity Determination Response to Public Comment Period, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Department of Environmental Protection, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 37-38)
    - Department of Environmental Protection, 1997-2002 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Department of Environmental Protection, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Department of Environmental Protection, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Department of Environmental Protection, Air Quality, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Department of Environmental Protection, Bureau of Air Quality, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Department of Environmental Protection, Bureau of Air Quality, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Department of Environmental Protection, Clean Air Act, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Department of Environmental Protection, Clean Air Update, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Department of Environmental Protection, Compliance Advisory Meeting, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Department of Environmental Protection, Correspondence, 1998-2000 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Department of Environmental Protection, Environmental Quality Board, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Department of Environmental Protection, Environmental Quality Board, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Department of Environmental Protection, Information Requested, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Department of Environmental Protection, Technical and Compliance Assistance Program, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Department of Environmental Resources, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Department of Transportation, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Dirty Dinosaur Campaign, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Emissions, 1995-2000 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Emissions, E-Check Auto Emissions Inspection, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Emissions, Skolnick Notes and Studies, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Emissions, Vehicle Emission and Inspection Maintenance Program Advisory Committee, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Environmental Protection Agency, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Environmental Protection Agency, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Environmental Protection Agency, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Environmental Protection Agency, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Environmental Protection Agency, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
    - Environmental Protection Agency, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Environmental Protection Agency, Air Quality Standards, undated (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
    - Environmental Protection Agency, Inspection and Maintenance, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Environmental Protection Agency, Liberty Borough Non-Attainment, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Environment, 1990-1997 (Box 6, Folder 9-10)
    - Environmental Articles, 1991-1998 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Environmental Articles, 1993-1996 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Environmental Articles, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Environmental Articles, 1994-1997 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Environmental Articles, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Environmental Articles, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Environmental Groups, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Environmental Journals, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Environmental Letters to the Editor, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Environmental Synopsis, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - GASP, 1989-1991 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - GASP, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - GASP, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - GASP, 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - GASP, undated (Box 6, Folder 25-26)
    - GASP, Board Meeting, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - GASP, Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - GASP, Financial, 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - GASP, Legal, EPA Lawsuit, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - GASP, Legal, Liberty Borough, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - GASP, Meetings, Minutes, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - GASP, Newsletters, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - GASP, Strategic Plan, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Methane Gas in Monroeville, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Miscellaneous, 1994-2000 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Miscellaneous, Citizens Guide to Effective State Air Quality Planning, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Miscellaneous, Conformity Stakeholders, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Miscellaneous, Correspondence, 1991-1995 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Miscellaneous, Delaware Valley Regional Planning Commission, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Miscellaneous, Environmental Datage Fund, undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Miscellaneous, Fine Particulates, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 42)